-♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, AD
♪ There was a guy named Joel
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked
at Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses didn't like himso they shot him into space ♪
♪♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies
♪ The worst we can find
♪ La-la-la
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
♪ La-la-la
♪ Now, keep in mind,
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La-la-la
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends
♪ Robot roll call
-Cambot!
-Pan left!
-Gypsy!
-Hi, girl!
-Tom Servo!
-What a cool guy!
-Cro-o-o-ow!
-He's a wisecracker.
-♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts,
la-la-la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax
♪ For "Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
♪♪
-And God bless Joel and Gypsy.
-And all the aliens
that have visited this ship.
-Hi, everybody.
Welcome to Satellite of Love.
When you got a job like ours,
you have
to believe in a higher power.
-30 seconds to commercial sign.
-And God bless Data
and his really cool robot
named Lal.
-And R2-D2 and all the extras
in "Westworld."
-And RoboCop, even though
I thought he got a raw deal,
but it's really none
of my business.
Oh, and all those early versions
that were just there
for comic relief.
-And, uh, ED-209,
though I don't know
why they'd make a robot
that can't walk down stairs.
-And God bless Cherry 3000.
-Oh, yeah.
And God bless Galaxina.
-Yeah!
-Okay, and who else?
-Oh...
-Do we have to?
-Yes.
-I don't want to.
I'm not --
-Yeah, you have to.
-Okay.
-God bless Twinkie.
-Commercial sign in
5, 4, 3, 2...
Commercial sign now.
-Amen.
♪♪
-Come on,
we have to pray for them.
If we can pray for them,
we can pray for anybody.
-I don't want to pray
for the mad scientists.
-Yeah, Joel.Why do we have to pray for
them?
-Well, I think they're watching,and they control my oxygen.
-We don't want you
to pray for us.
We want you to pray tous.
Isn't that right, Frank?
-[Breathing heavily]
Don't look at me!
I said never look at me!
Mommy! Mommy!
-Frank!
-Aah!
-Calm down.
It's time for the invention
exchange again, Joel,
and we'll go first because we'vegot a party to go to later.
Well, this summer's fashions
cry out with jubilant
2-inch armor plating,
saucy turrets,
and shells a-plenty.
You can really clear
the beaches this summer
with our new tank tops.
-That's right.
The best beach party ever was
the one at Normandy.
Beach Blanket Bingo --
Ayuck, mm --
is now Beach Blanket Bombing
with the latest
in fashion artillery.
-That's right.
Shelling on the beach
takes on a whole new meaning.
Let's get in position, Frank.
Ready...aim...fire!
Now let's see how we've done.
-Hey. Wait a minute.
I can hear the war.
-Oh, knock that off.
-Oh, oh, look --
-Now, lookit here.
Look,
there's still a little red.
I'm sorry.
I can't give you the bear.
-Damn! Why?!
-Well, what do you think, Joel?
-Boy, we sure think differently,thank goodness, you know?
-You know, you guys took
something fun and made it evil,
whereas I took something evil,
and I'm making it fun.
Check it out.
It's the tickle bazooka.
Alright?
-Wow.
-It's for those times
when just a normal tickle
isn't enough.
I based it on the premise
of what the pundits
Firesign Theater once spoke --
"Fighting's out of style.
Fun's where the fear is."
-Yeah.
-See, it's got a, uh,
feather bayonet
for hand-to-hand tickling.
-[Laughs]
Cut it out.
-Okay.
And then, if you really want
to have some big blast
of ballistic hilarity,
there's the mirth mortar.
Let me show you.
-Uh-oh.
Brace yourself.
-Okay.
-Head for cover.
-Smile.
-[Laughs]
-What do you think?
-That is so neat.
We could base a whole party
around that.
We could all get in
our fuzzy feet-y pajamas
and jump up and down on the bed.
-Look, the only party
we're going to is the one
where we dance on your grave.
-Oh, will I be invited?
-You'll be the guest of honor.
-[Chuckles]-Now, tell them about the movie.
I got to get out of this thing.
I'm chafing like a bear.
-Well, Joel, this week's movie
is called "Catalina Caper,"
and it is delightful.
It's a veritable
feel-good movie,
a lighthearted romp,
a triumph of the human spirit!
Thank you, Tommy Kirk,
for making us laugh about love.
Again.
And it's got a great theme song.You're gonna love it.
♪ Never ever, ever
-Frank! Incoming!
♪ Ever sing anywhere ever
[Singing gibberish]
[Laughter]
[Alarm blaring]
-Movie sign!
[Laughter resumes]
-That was funny.
Oh, fun.
We have fun.
-Huh.
-Great fun.
-What gives?
-Hmm?
-Huh.
-Hmm. Interesting.
What's wrong
with this guy's feet?
-He has prehensile toes.
-What do you suppose
Frogman's legs taste like?
-Uh, like San Diego
chicken legs, probably?
-Look!
-♪ You may steal a kiss
-Hmm.
-♪ It's permissible
♪ You can return this
-Ha! Ohh!
-So, uh, what's in the can?
-♪ Or steal an embrace
-I think it's, uh,
dehydrated water.
-Oh!
♪ It's replaceable
if he should fret ♪
-Oh, a scuba film.
-Hmm.
Jacques Cousteau
meets the Pink Panther.
-♪ Steal his sweater
and love letter ♪
♪ Read it and burn it
-By this time, I --
-Hey, come on.
-Huh?
-Just don't.
-Okay. Okay. Sorry.
-So, what's a Catalina caper?
-Uh, it's one of those
little balls you find
when you're eating
peel-and-eat shrimp.
-Mmm!
Sorry, Charlie.Only the best titles are killed.
-Starring Tommy Kirk.
Why must Spock die?
-♪ You may steal his heart
-Oh, Robert Donner.
I went to his party.
-♪ It's the best part
a woman can get ♪
-Yeah, I wonder what
she's harping on about.
-[Chuckles]
-Hey, who's this guy --
Jim Begg Sue Casey Lyle
Waggoner Mike Blodgett?
-♪ Man, it will whip you
-Nice measurements.
36, 2, 85?
-♪ Play it clever
♪ Never, never steal
anything wet ♪
♪♪
-I think that fish
is gonna spit up again.
♪♪
-Who's afraid of Venita Wolf,
anyway?
-[Chuckles]
♪ Steal his shaggy
little baggies ♪
-Charlie,
they cut off my thumbs!
-♪ Make sure they're dry first
-Special guest star,
Peter Mamakos.
-♪ You're not a seal
-Oh, Little Richard.
I've heard of him.
He's not as famous
as Peter Mamakos.
-Mnh-mnh.
-Oh, he's playing a trick
on that fish.
-Oh, yeah.
Feel good about
kicking a fish's butt.
That's real nice.
-♪ If crime doesn't pay
♪ You can both love your way
out of debt ♪
-Oh, screenplay
written in crayon.
-What's Clyde Ware?
-♪ Keep on stealing
all his affection ♪
-Sal Mungo --
Rebel without a gauze.
-♪ Ever steal anything wet
♪ Steal anything wet
-That's the Bullwinkle show,
isn't it?
-Yeah.
-Here's something
you'll really like.
-Sholem!
♪ Steal anything wet
-Look out!
[Laughter]
♪♪
-Wow.
That is really good animation.
♪♪
-Now I'll set fire
to the Walt Whitman books,
then I'll burn the pile
of "Catcher in the Ryes."
-Come on, you ho-daddies.
Let's burn some books!
-Whoo-hoo!
Burn the witch!
-Burn the witch!
We shall cleanse the Earth
with fire!
-How do you know she's a witch?
-Well, these Klan meetings
have really lightened up.
Look at that.
-Now, that's what I call art --
scantily clad women
and a Huey Lewis News
is on the radio.
This is the kind of padding
I like to see in a film.
-Throw another Beach Boy
on the fire.
♪♪
-Whoa!
And so the white Aryan Youth
dance around the funeral pyre.
-You know,
this is really good sound,
and it was before Dolby.
-Dolby jealous?
I don't know.
-Meanwhile,
in a dark, impenetrable void,
Jean-Paul Sartre was
a-movin' and a-groovin'.
-No exit, baby.
-Oh, looks like they're, uh,
in the night gallery.
-This portrait --
a man who smokes more
than Edward R. Murrow
or Lillian Hellman.
-I'm William Conrad
for "First Alert."
When you're heading
down to the refrigerator
and the power goes out...
-Hey, it's Steve Higgins.
-What, you mean the star of
"The Higgins Boys and Gruber,"
as seen on The Comedy Channel?
-Yeah!
-Wow!
-This must be
Tommy Kirk's Oscar.
He's so good that they --
they gave it to him
before they started the film.
-Huh.
-He beat out Troy Donahue
and Frankie Avalon.
-Huh?
"Yeah, I beat out Dom DeLuise
and James Coco for this role.
Now beat it."
♪♪
-He's looking
for that string quartet.
-An original Red Skelton.
That's incredibly valuable.
-"Good night.
May God bless."
"This painting is blue.
Don't work blue.
It's such a waste."
-"I'm gonna put this
in a frame that fits."
-Gee,
it looks like a garage rag.
-"Sims Security.
I'm the one who cracked
that crime at One Potato, Two.
I beat out Al Molinaro
and Jesse White for this role."
-Wow, that's a "Family Circus."
-Wow! What's --
-From Hank Ketcham's
Bil Keane collection.
-Looks kind of like a Ruben.
-Paul Reuben?
You mean Pee-wee Herman?
-No!
-D'oh!
-Oh!
-Oops!
He broke Tommy's Oscar.
Well, I did the same thing
to his Pulitzer.
-"Huh? What?
Hmm? Hmm?"
-He's putting it together.
-Oh, relax.
They'll just think
it's a Rothko now, see?
-Yeah, just, just --
-Or a Mondrian, perhaps.
-Boy, that's a big whistle!
You know how to whistle,
don't you?
You just put your lips together
and cut to the boat.
[Chuckles]
-Bangkok, Oriental city.
"Koyaanisqatsi:
Life out of Balance."
-No, this film is a fantasy
'cause you generally
don't see cabs in
Southern California like this.
-America's fastidious
and well-groomed youth
living a clean lifestyle,
pumping their clean,
hard-won dollars
into a clean economy that
is sunny, colorful Catalina.
♪♪
Hmm.
-And this one right there.
-Fire Island?
Well, look at this.
"White people voted
the best people in the world."
-"Young white male
still on top."
-"NEA denies Bil Keane grant."
-Oh, it looks like Brutus
and Popeye after SlimFast.
-Olive standing
right behind them.
-Hmm.
Not bad.
-What's that supposed to mean?
-I'm going onboard, Bob.
-"I know.
I can see it in your eyes."
♪♪
-Mother!
Charlie Baby's
come back to the nest!
-Welcome home, delinquent.
-"Oh, thanks,
but we're felons now."
-Hi, I'm Bob Draper.
School must have
assigned you his keeper.
-Don Pringle.
-Heir
to the potato chip fortune.
-Never seen
the big water before.
I figured a summer on the island
to put a little juice
in the old battery.
-I think you'll like it,
if you can take him.
-Like it?
You should have seen him
coming up the coast.
I don't think
they sell bikinis in Arizona.
-Oh, they sell them.
But I never saw so many
trying to cover so much
with so little success.
-Thank you, Winston Churchill.
-Don't let it discourage you.
I felt the same way myself once.It only gets better.
-Say!
-Oh, talk about discouraged.
Have you seen the new crop?
-"Man, my corn is as high
as an elephant's eye."
-Decisions, decisions.I've seen three exactly my type.
-Yeah, real dumb!
-Welp, somebody stole
another painting.
-There's the final
boarding whistle.
-Yeah, we'll dig you later.
-I'll be around, if only to
keep you guys out of trouble.
-[Chuckles] I love this
good-natured ribbing.
[Light laughter]
-Ah, what do you suppose
this guy's up to?
Hmm. Ohh!
-D'oh!
-I don't believe it.
-He saw Big Jake.
-"Here,
let me help you up with that.
Say, that gangplank really
gave you what-for, friend."
-[Chuckles]
He should wear a truss.
-Okay.
Cue the made-for-TV music.
Love -- exciting and new!
-Duh.
-Smell that air, huh?
Take a look around.
-Air, water.
-"Air, water."
You're pretty observant there,
pal.
-...far more exhilarating
diversions below deck.
-"I didn't know you were
holding, my compadre."
-Maybe you're not ready.
-I'm ready! I'm ready!
-"I think the farm
will be good for me."
-I plan the agenda.
In Phoenix, you showed me
all the ugly glories
of Gila monsters
and cactus and plants.
On Catalina,
believe it, man, I am king.
Surfing and girls.
Big game fishing and girls.
Scuba diving...
-Guys.
-...and girls.
-He sounds like Curt Gowdy,
doesn't he?
-Or Hugh Hefner.
-I'm in your capable hands.
-Alright.
And we start the summer
with a bang.
Like we start
right now below deck.
-You mean "deck."
-He said "deck."
-Huh?
-I've been driving all night.
-Breathe, live,
if Muhammad won't come
to the mountain.
-Hmm.
-I think that's inappropriate
social behavior.
-"Excuse me.
I gotta go invent the Walkman.
After this."
♪♪
-"And so I want
to join the Forum."
-Hey!
-Hmm.
-Nice railing!
♪♪
-"May I re-tie your pants?"
-It sure is quiet out here.
-It wasquiet.
-What an idiot.
-I've never seen
the ocean before.
-Oh, then you've missed much.
-"Yes, it's only 75%
of the Earth's surface."
-I guess I have.
-There's a whole world
beneath all that.
And there is life --
all sizes, shapes, and colors.
-What gives?
-Huh?
-We sure could get hung up on ittomorrow night on the beach.
-"Yes.
I'm hung up on it right now.
Help me."
-...I dove into the sea
and began swimming underwater.
And there was this small fish.
-She's beautiful, Joel.
-He wasn't afraid of me at all.
-Hey, was she in the movie
"David and Lisa"?
-I think she's pretty.
-A fishing boat ahead
frightened it.
And I never saw
my little friend again.
-Hmm.
-You know,
there's a psychiatrist onboard.
I think he could
really help you.
-For the weekend,
perhaps longer.
Why?
-Great!
Because would you like
to go swimming with me?
-"With me and Edie Sedgwick
and Rod LaRod?"
-Oh, that would be wonderful,
but I'm afraid that --
-Don, baby.
Go get him!
-Say!
-Hey, we're done with the Forum.
We're Druids now.
-I'm in truth.
I can't help whatever
it is I do to them.
Come on! Let's go!
[Indistinct shouting]
-Oh!
-"I'd like to make their scene,
but they're a little weird,
and, hey, fishy,
fishy, fishy!
Come here, little
fishy, fishy."
-Hey, let's dig Little Richard,
really turn it on!
-"Little Richard?
I hate impressionists."
-Oh, you're thinking
of Rich Little.
-Oh.
-Now, pay attention, guys.
This scene is obviously
really important to the film.
-This is Little Richard.
-♪ Baby, baby, baby,
come along with me ♪
-Uh-oh. Uh-huh.
♪ We gonna scuba dive
in the deep blue sea ♪
-Dig. It.
-♪ Now, grab your tank
and grab your gear ♪
-Prince,
I hope you're watching this.
-♪ Now, come along with me
-Hey, we have a chair downstairswith that upholstery.
-I think --
Looks like a coffin lining.
-♪ We gonna dive in
and swim all about ♪
-Hey, get the funk
out of my face.
Come on.
-♪ Now at the party
-Dig it.
-♪ Scuba party
-Now, there's, uh,
really nothing we can say
about that, is there?
-At least not
during family hour.
-♪ Scuba party
-Hey, look, it's Alan Sues.
[Light laughter]
-♪ At the party
-Whoops.
-♪ Scuba party
-He's getting seasick.-♪ Now, won't you swim around?
♪ Don't you be no square
♪ Whoooo
-Hmm.
-I think I know
a bright, young singer
that's hopped up on goofballs
right now.
-Is he in this scene?
-Yes.
And his head's
about 10 feet tall.
-♪ We're gonna dive in
and swim all about ♪
♪ Move around,
just like the crowd ♪
-I like
the pencil-thin mustache.
-O-tay.
Hey, it's his band!
-Great, next we'll see Sly Stone
with the, uh...
"Up With People," probably.
-Ike Turner with The Cowsills.
They'll all be in casts.
-James Brown
and the Starland Vocal Band.
-Yeah! George Clinton with
the Ray Conniff Singers.
[Chuckles]
-"Like this, Mr. Richard?
How's this, huh?"
-Is there a history of epilepsy
in your family, boy?
-♪ We're gonna have some fun
without a doubt ♪
-You know, he's so hopped up,
uh, I think he's thinkinghe's at the Apollo or something.
-♪ At the party
-I like him.
Hey, it's Ron Howard's brother!
-"Ben!"
-♪ At the party
-♪ Ow!
♪ Scuba party
-Hey. Whoa.
-Looks like
Cousin Itt with a bob.
-♪ It's the only, only way
-♪ At the party
♪ Scuba party
-A swingin' bob.
-♪ We gonna dive in
and swim all about ♪
-Little Richard,
the only genuine talent
in this film.
-♪ Just like the crowd,
Now at the party ♪
♪ Ow! Ow! Ow!
-You know, those dancers
are standing on Dumpsters.
Would that
make them white trash?
♪ Oh, while at the party
-I'm glad we recycle.
-♪ Whooooo
-♪ The Nazi party
Everybody!
-You know, I'm feeling like
we're more at the dance thing
in "Laugh-In" kind of.
-Ha!
Welp, you were great.
Now leave.
Out the back door.
-Well, it's just us, Timmy,
when you graduate
from Pat Boone University.
-So, Falco leaves the Calypso.
[Horn blares]
And another painting is stolen.
-Ah, Is this where
they filmed "The Boatniks"?
It looks really familiar.
-Now local news.
Police investigations failed
to turn up new clues...
-"My skull is an amplifier."
-...of the priceless
Chu Dynasty scroll
from a private
Los Angeles museum.
-"Yeah, I did it. I did it.
I'm proud, man."
-But police remain
stumped at this point.
-"Ugh!"
-"Hey,
you got puke on my radio."
-"No, you got radio in my puke."
-Actually, I think he's, uh,
working on a new script.
-Must be the screenwriter.
-Yeah.
-Makeup.
-"Oh, magic balcony,
take me away
from this kooky crowd."
♪♪
-"I'm the white guy
who runs this ship.
I could take out this whole
crowd if I wanted to.
I'm that powerful.
Disperse!"
♪♪
-It's time to vacuum
the pool, I think.
-"Hey, you got room
for one more extra?
Wait for me!"
-No, they got a fat,
dumpy guy in this already.
-Oh, sorry.
-They're diving for chum.
-Gun it!
-Yay!
-Gun it now!
Chop 'em up!
-"Petticoat Junction"!
-Hey, whoa!
[All cheer]
-Hey, what gives?
He's the guy with the implant.
-Carol?
Uh, Carol?
Are you Carol?
-Harvey?
-Carol?
-How's your little fish?
-"We have a proper love."
-♪ Do-do-do-do-do
-"I got your stick, Mr. Luthor."
♪♪
-Ohh.
-"Oh, would you give me that?!"
-"Sorry!"
"Man, I'm too tired to even do
one of my famous pratfalls."
-"Um, I'm all hurtin' and hot
and hurtin' and stuff."
-"Now, guys,
just sit right back,
and you'll hear a tale."
-Crete. Ancient civilization.
Mykonos. Modern civilization.
-Ah.
-Hmm.
-Mel Brooks, Anne Bancroft,
and Dom DeLuise
in "Boatniks 2."
-...bases loaded,
just like we planned.
-Oh, shut up.
-Shut up.
-Ahh.
-[Slurps]
-Lawrence, you're --
We're really proud of you.
You're a credit
to your profession.
-Village idiot.
-Well, I do the best I can
with what I've got.
-Which isn't
a whole hell of a lot.
-Let's go downstairs,
and I'll show you.
-Mm.
Ted is below.
-I'm afraid our son
wouldn't approve
of our little business venture.
-Your son? What is this?
"Who's Afraid
of Virginia Woolf?"
-I know what you mean.
-"It's not your son, George."
-You just can't trust a kid
who don't follow baseball.
-But trust a guy with
a dumb Crayola hat.
-Hey, it's filled with M&M's.
-Hmm!
-Neat.
-Long ones.
-"Well, let's see here.
You are a child of the universe,no less than the trees of..."
-It's "Desiderata"!
-What do you think, Anne?
-It's a Howard Johnson
place mat.
"I don't think you won
the riddle contest."
-Well, with the equipment
we have below,
it shouldn't take long.
-Say!
-I should have the duplicate
finished in less than 24 hours.
-Excellent.
-She's something.
-We're a great little team!
-Oh, shut up.
-Yeah, not enough for
an infield, but...
It's the William Burroughs
figurehead!
♪♪
-"Even theymake me sick."
-Hey, why two?
-Hmm.
-One for the genuine.
One for the duplicate.
-And one for the little girl
who lives down the lane.
-Jodie Foster?
-Yeah.
-Now we know the entire plot.
Thanks a lot.
-Hey, have we contacted
our fat Greek pigeon yet?
-Hmm?
-Friend Lakopolous
arrived last night.
-He's the top-o-lis.
-You know, I hear he's got
a whole castle filled
with stolen art treasures
stashed away in Switzerland.
-Popolis.
-How come a millionaire
like Dino Lakopolous
wants to be a crook?
-'Cause he's in-scrop-ulous.
-...profession to procure
one's taste, Lawrence.
-Oh. I see.
-Hey, can I light that for you?
-First we show him the picture.
He okays it, right?
-Right.
-Mm-hmm.
-Then we slip him
the phony scroll
that you're gonna paint tonight.-Mm-hmm.
-Then Donald goes in
where the others have been.
-Then you'll return the originalto its rightful owner.
-And then return that shirt
to Robin Williams.
-I mean,
how come we can't keep it?
-We certainly can't keep it.
That would be dishonest.
-Aw.
-Well, the deal
we're pulling on Lakopolous
ain't exactly kosher, you know.
-Oh, hold the mayo.
-Ah, but not quite the same.
Lakopolous is a proud thief.
That's the only way
he'll do business.
It's expected
one will try to cheat him.
-Like Nixon.
-Ah, so you've outdone
yourself this time.
Oh, you're simply glowing
with imagination.
-That's sweat.
-Ah, dear,
I'm really very proud of you.
-Thank you, dearest.
I must admit I do have a flair
for this sort of thing.
-Alcoholism?
-True, true.
-Bet he won't fall.
-Oh?
Well, well,
we better beat it, guys.
-Oh, yeah.
-Beat what?
[Laughter]
-That kills me.
-Joel, could you tell us about
this thing called the '60s?
-Yeah, I'm amused and fascinatedby such an environment
that the beautiful
creepy girl existed in.
-Well, I was just a little kid
when it happened,
but I can tell you guys
what I remember.
-Okay.
-Oh, yeah.
You're so much older than
you're younger than that now.
-Yeah, whatever, Crow.
Anyway, Cambot,
could you run that music?
Yeah, cool.
-Hey!
-Well, it was a lot simpler timeback then.
You know, like --
I'll give you an example.
Like, it wasn't uncommon at all
for your mom to come
and serve you a great,
big char-broiled steak
while she smoked
and, uh, drank a tab
and made your dad another
Manhattan for the road.
-And now it's just breakfast.
-Oh, go on!
-Yeah, there were seatbelts
in cars, but nobody used them.
Pre-sweetened cereal,
subliminal messages.
-Drugs.
-People smoked openly
on "The Tonight Show."
-Hey, uh, tell us about
the Rat Pack again.
-Oh, okay.
Well, as you know,
uh, Frank Sinatra
was Chairman of the Board,
and everybody else
filed on in line,
except for Jerry Lewis.
He had had a falling out
with Dean Martin,
and they already had
chosen Joey Bishop to be
their comic relief already.
So he was kind of out of luck.
But Dean was tall and tan
and quick with a song.
And he just had
to say the word...
-Sex.
-...and coo-coo chicks would
file on up
to the hospitality suite
and massage Peter Lawford's neck
and make everybody groovy drinks
while they took
important phone calls
from places like Palm Springs
and, um, the White House.
-Ooh.
Turn me on, Batman.
-Until it was time
for Frank Sinatra,
the Chairman of the Board,
to come out of the sauna,
and he'd say the words
and the dollies
would go take a nap.
-Free love.
-Subliminal messages.
Oh, uh, tell us about
the rabbits, Joel.
-Yeah, that's a good one.
-The rabbits. Okay.
Meanwhile, in the Windy City,
um, Hugh Hefner was cooking up
his own groovy scene
in the aptly named
Playboy Mansion.
-Oh, wow!
-There was George Kennedy
and George Hamilton
and Tony Curtis
and Bill Bixby were
all in his court.
Sophisticated men
who knew their racket...
-I think you're swinging
into high.
-Yeah!
-Yeah, anyway,
there was, um, like,
Twiggy and Abby
and Peter, Paul, and Mary,
Dion, Donovan, uh, uh,
Melanie, uh, uh,
Abraham, Martin,
and John, you know?
-And so, they just went by
their first names like that?
-Yeah, like you, Crow.
-Hey!
-And there were typewriters,
but nobody used them.
And women were called "girls."
-Wow!
-Of course.
-And businessmen wore
double-breasted suits,
had double chins,
drank double Bourbons,
straight, no chaser...
-Cool!
-...before, during, and after
important business meetings
and, uh, summit talks.
-Everybody believed
what the president said.
Why shouldn't they?
Sexually provocative humor
wasn't on TV.
It was on cocktail napkins,
and we liked it that way.
Toys had metal edges
and little pieces
that were breakable
and would fit into your mouth.
-Gobots.
-They would take and make
playground equipment
out of stainless steel,
then haul it up onto asphalt,
where you could get hurt.
Parents were actually told
to spank their kids.
My mom actually made me
go and get the belt,
you know, in front of company,
and that was
really frustrating...
-Joel, Joel, Joel, Joel!
-...because once they made me
take a bath in the front yard.
-Joel!
Why can't you be
like everyone else
and just remember
the good things about the '60s?
-Yeah, like Woodstock!
-Oh, the Woodstock. Great.
Okay, "No, Joel,
you can't go to Woodstock.
You're 9 years old.
We're going to the opening
of the new Century Store.
Oh, yeah, on Echo Lane.
Three days of peace,
love, and pizza rolls."
-Uh, people, Joel's
in a lot of pain.
-Oh, boy, Peter from Acts...
-We'll be right back.
..."moved freely among men."
There were --
Oh, did I mention
there were drugs at that time?
-Yeah.
-And then...
♪♪
[Bell tolling]
-Yeah, and the only shoesthey had were PF Flyers and Keds
and that was it.
-Joel!
-Nothing --
No Pumps, no nothing.
-Okay. Okay, Joel.
Okay, you can cool it now.
You okay?
-Yeah.
-"Hey, look at the prow
on that steamer.
Let's climb aboard."
-Whoa.
Ahoy, matey.
-Hello, Betty!
-Don!
-"Yeah,
that's one of my chicks."
♪♪
-Turn to!
Turn to, you idiot!
-Turn to what?
-The Comedy Channel!
-Turn to!
-A little promo there, gang.
-Whoa!
-[Chuckles]
-"Hello! Hello!"
-"Hiya, Shoil.
-"Hello."
-Shall we have breakfast
at the club, dear?
-That would be nice.
-"I wet myself."
Ew!
-"Thank goodness this briefcase
is a personal
floatation device."
-[Imitates trombone]
-Love that trombone.
-"Welcome to White Island.
Acting like we deserve
this kind of lifestyle."
-Only the best-looking girls
get to be starfish.
-Chuck, it's great
to have you home.
-"Hey, it's great to see you.
What -- What's your name?"
-"Hi. Want to trade hair?"
-You sure made the scene
out there.
-It's all your fault.
You weren't supposed
to be here until tomorrow.
-We finished our exams
and split a day early.
-"Hey, how are things
in the Fatherland?"
-...hung up on the mainland
for a couple days.
-"Yeah, mom got hung up on
the tennis pro at the club."
-This must be Don Pringle.-You named it right, Miss Bunny.
-"I understand your ruffles
have ridges."
Chuck mentioned you were coming
in his last letter.
We'll try to make your summer
as eventful as possible.
-Oh, wow!
-Well, I'm prepared
to defend myself
against anything he might have
said about me, if I have to.
-He said you were a jerk.
-Something tells me apologies
are in order, Miss Bunny.
-Miss Bunny?
-Ohh.
-"Now, McHale,
what the hell are you doing?!"
-That guy looks like, uh,
Ralph on "Green Acres,"
doesn't he?
-Are you folks alright?
-Oh, yeah, sure, we're fine.
Fine, all except my assistant.
He's a little wet.
I left him onboard.
-I'm awfully sorry.
That was pretty stupid of me.
-Oh, think nothing of it,
young lady.
Those things do happen.
-"You are blonde, after all."
-I'm Arthur Duval.
This is my wife, Anne,
our son, Tad.
-Charlie Moss. My sister, Tina,
and this is Don Pringle.
-Tad, Tina.
-Tad, Jean. Tad, Tom.
-Paul, Bob.
-Carol, Ted, Alice.
Stop it!
-Isn't that the Sloanes' yacht
you're using?
-Uh, yes, matter of fact, it is.-Oh, the Sloanes.
We met the Sloanes in
Monte Carlo last season.
Charming people.
-"They lie so gracefully."
-...they insisted that we have
the use of their yacht.
-Yeah.
-Is this your first trip here?
-Well, yes.
We haven't had much opportunity
to visit your little,
uh, Treasure Island.
However, we are interested
in learning all there is
to know about treasure,
aren't we, Anne?
-Oh, yes!
[Laughter]
[Indistinct talking]
-"Hey, I just became a Mormon."
-I'm with you, Miss Bunny.
-Miss Bunny?
-Tad, why don't you come along?
We're gonna split with the boat
for some scuba diving.
-Oh, but of course!
Oh, that's a very
kind invitation.
Tad's been cooped up aboard shipsince we arrived.
-"Tied to a mast."
-Give you a chance
to enjoy yourself, son,
meet some people your own age,
like Miss Bunny here.
-"Get away from
your effeminate father."
-Live a little.
-No, thanks.
Next time around?
-"Not nearly enough
beautiful women for me."
-Dad, can I see you
for a minute?
-Certainly, son.
-Uh, excuse me, dear.
I'm going up to the hotel
to get another sun hat.
-"You know, Dad,
Mom's really hot."
-Dad,
why did we come to Catalina?
-We came to enjoy ourselves.
Why?
-Whenever you and mother
come to enjoy yourselves,
it means you're involved
in some kind of a shady deal.
-"Now, I know
you've been hanging around
with that Dave Del Dotto guy."
-I'm glad your mother
isn't here to listen --
-When you talk like that,
I know you're up to no good.
-"And when you smell like that,
somebody must die."
-...shady deal could
we possibly be involved in
on a small island like this?
-I don't know.
But whatever it is,
you and mother
are right smack
in the middle of it.
-Tad, I give you my word.
-Goodie!
-Your mother and I
are here on a holiday
and for no other reason.
-Yeah.
-Now, I'm starved.
Let's get something to eat.
-Yeah, and when you give
that take to the camera,
what do you expect?
-"Oh, my Dad, I love him so."
-Uh-oh. Hold it, you guys.
-[Chuckles]
-This is gonna be funny.
-Hey, yeah.
-Now, just let it play out.
I want to get all
the great humor in it.
-Get ready to laugh.
-The great physical comedian
of our time.
-Heck of a walk
from the mainland.
-Ohh!
-And --
And then it gets funny, right?
-I don't believe it.
-Hmm.
-Ah.
Oh, well...
-Maybe not.
-Was that the funny part, Joel?
-I guess.
-This is the place!
Okay, Miss Bunny,
drop the anchor!
-"I already did."
-Wow!
-Welp, we need
a new shower curtain.
-It doesn't leave much
to the imagination.
-"I don't have one."
-Ever do any diving, Don?
-"Oh, yeah!"
-Not quite the same.
There's a trick to it.
Just remember one thing.
-"You'll be underwater."
-Breathe normally,
but through your mouth,
not your nose.
-Bottoms up!
-He's always saying that.
We don't know why.
-Hey, it looks like a gas.
-You better use the ladder.
-Oxygen.
-I'm on the diving team,
remember?
-Congratulations.
Now use the ladder.
-"But I said I was
on the diving team."
-It's the Pueblo.
-It's alright.
Just kids.
Hmm, very interesting.
-"But stupid."
-What is it, Mr. Lakopolous?
Let me have a look.
-Don't get excited, Borman.
Too young for you.
-That isn't fair.
-Say!
-I'll take care
of everything else.
-An exchange student.
-I called Dr. Duval.
-Now, Barbara, buff my head.
-Unfortunately, Duval
is a thief, a clever one.
Remember that.
You must trust no one
and be very careful.
-"And remember
something else, too --
An object in motion
tends to stay in motion
unless acted up on
by an unbalanced force.
Now get out."
-She's a much better swimmer.
-There's also my only sister's
only boy...
-Doesn't sound very Greek,
does he?
-...and a very stupid one.
You, the purported art expert,
I can replace.
-Okay, Daddy Warbucks.
-If you fail me in this,
friend Borman,
I promise you a long walk home.
-"And I'll kill you again."
-"Should I go put the horse's
head in my bed again?"
"Hi, Kaiser Wilhelm,
you kooky monarch."
[Laughs]
-Lakopolous is still out there.
-Yeah.
-Is that your hand?
-You know,
I'd give a month's pay to know
why he's got such a sudden
interest in California waters.
-Five bucks?
-Sure must be nice
to have all that bread...
-Toast.
-...cruise around the world
on your own yacht.
-"Eat all the fruit,
throw away the rind."
-He'll die in the ocean,
and when he does...
-♪ Headin' out to Eden
-...those vultures
that work for him will pick
his little world clean.
-"Hmm. Nice analogy.
I know I hired you
for something, Rod McKuen."
-"Let's break for chow."
-I'll see you later.
-Great.
-They are a couple
of salty tars.
-What will I do now?
-Pull down your facemask.
-Pull down your what?!
-Huh?
-Can you breathe alright?
-"I can't breathe!
I can't breathe!"
-...but stay close
to the surface.
-Wow, this is the weirdest
Lamaze class I've ever seen.
-"It's all blue,
and it's wet and stuff!"
-...while you're still ahead?
-My nose does!
It won't stop breathing.
-Let's try it again.
Take a couple of deep breaths
through your mouth.
-Ah!
-"Oh, that's this thing, right?
The slit in my face?" Yeah.
-If I'm not up this time in two
minutes, fake it without me.
-Fake it?
-You ready to give it a try?
-I'm with you.
-Hang on to my waist.
-Anything you say, teacher.
-Hey, hey!
-...you've got the wrong sport.
-When does it become
the right sport?
-When ESPN merges with
the Playboy Channel.
Now, get under water!
-...remember, breathe
through your mouth.
-"Not through your hands."
♪♪
-"By this time, my" -- Sorry.
So-- I -- That was me.
I'm sorry.
-Make some Jacques Cousteau
jokes instead, will you?
"What would happen
if I turn off the air?"
-"Say, I hear Ivan Tors
is casting a new adventure show
in the Keys with a dolphin."
-"What happens
if I see a leviathan?"
-"Don't pay full price.
Get the shrimp."
♪♪
-"Hmm.
Time to impress some people.
Then I'll go out and start
a line of clothes called Polo.
Oh, I look like Phil Harris,
don't I?"
-I know this Borman guy.-"He'll cast us in 'Excalibur'!"
-...gotta know about, uh,
killing and things like that.
-"Ohh."
-Oh, he's got it up here.
Do you know that
he knows the batting average
of every White Stocking players
of the 1876 season?
-Oh, shut up!
-Shut up!
-Somebody has
to check the painting,
but in broad daylight
and -- and so soon.
Oh, boy.
I should have stayed
in real estate.
-Yeah.
"Oh, that's my watch.
It does that
every quarter hour."
-Cast off.
-Hmm?
-"Cast off"?
"Oh, it hurts when I think.
Let's see..."
-Cast off the line, idiot.
-"Oh, the line, yeah.
Right, uh...
The rabbit goes around the hole,
and then it comes
out the other...
But it -- Ohh."
-Ohh.
Meanwhile, on Bruce Wayne's
stately yatcht...
Yacht.
Pardon me.
-Hey, there's a boat out there.
You think that's him?
-No, it's just a skiff.
-"That's us, you fool.
It's an exterior shot."
-Scuba diving and things.
-Hmm.
-Well, if you ask me,
we're sticking our necks way outplaying ball in his park.
-"You don't even have a neck."
-How come we got to show the
real scroll to Lakopolous' man?
-One thing you must learn,
Lawrence, is that you show
the genuine item
to bait the hook,
proving to the buyer
that you have it
is one of the distasteful
but necessary things
about this business.
-"Tell me when you're done."
-Maybe he won't show up anyway.
-Borman specified the cove
away from the harbor
for the rendezvous.
I doubt that he'll miss it.
-"Now, get away from me,
little man."
-Patience, Lawrence -- one otherthing that you must learn.
Now, drop anchor.
-"Oh, there's that
watch of mine again."
-Where?
-Will you get out of here?!
-Okay, alright.
-Oh, great!
-Remember that last time
we were a little disappointed.
I think now
we're gonna see a scene
that's wrought with comic
possibilities, alright?
-Classic.
-The real mechanics of comedy.
Tragedy tomorrow,
comedy tonight.
-Comedy tonight.
-Yeah.
-The Jacques Tati
of the boating world.
-Yep.
-I'm ready.
-Monsieur Hulot in Catalina.
-You know it's gonna be funny.
He's wearing corduroy.
-That's right.
Gonna get doused.
-This is --
This is the funny right here.
-Uh-oh.
-Oh!
He's gonna catch his foot
in the rope, right?
Oh, no!
Number 27 -- the old boat
and the anchor trick.
-But where's the funny?
-[Laughs]
-Hey!
-Oh! Didn't come out
of his tuck in time.
Russian judge gives him a 3.
-That wasn't really,
uh, funny at all.
It was kind of stupid, actually.
"Hi, I'm the bad guy.
Remember me?"
-[Chuckles]
-"Hey!
There's a world up there."
Hmm.
-Hmm?
-"Candygram.
Land shark."
-"I am Death."
-"Have you ever read
our Watchtower?"
-On time, eh, gentlemen?
-[Chuckles]
Where's the scroll?
-"What scroll?"
-Did you bring the money?
-Mr. Lakopolous is
not a stupid man.
-"Sure, he drools and sings
camp songs, but..."
-...arrange a fair exchange.
-Gee, it's hard to take him
seriously in that suit.
-Yeah.
Uh, you're soaking in it.
-[Laughs]
-"So, you, uh,
swim around here much?
Weren't you a little hard
on the fat guy?"
-Yeah.
-Hmm.
-[Whistling]
"Uh, don't you have a line?
Oh, uh, here he is."
-Look, the water fuzz!
-Hmm?
-Water fuzz?!
-Yet, some call them water pigs.
-Oh, no, you don't!
Give me that!
-"Oh, yes, I do."
Whoa!
-Uh-oh.
-There it goes.
-Down she goes.
-"Ah, please, love me."
Oh!
-"Huh?! What?!"
-"Spinner, Paddlefoot, quick!
Clutch is in trouble!"
-How do you like it down there?
-Groovy!
Once I get the hang of it,
I may give up deserts
and rattlesnakes for life.
-Yeah!
Water fuzz.
They're wet.
They care.
Tonight's episode,
"Death Ahoy!"
-Yo, ho, ho,
and a bottle of death!
-Tinker, tailor,
soldier, dead man.
-Michael,
row your murder ashore.
-[Chuckles]
Hallelujah.
No, Timmy! No, no!
Darn fool kid!
-Skippy's in trouble!
-Should have known.
-Ah, you just ate.
Be careful down there.
-Shouldn't be under there.
-Oh. Huh.
-"Well, they're gone.
Let's form a girl group."
-Oh, looks like somebody swabbedthe deck with somebody's butt.
[Chuckles]
[Imitating music]
-Along about that time,
the old Duke boys
got a little trouble
coming their way
in the form of Mr. Skinman.
-Huh?
-It is cold down there.
Just...
-"Greetings.
I come from the --
Huh?!"
-"Come on, come on!
Give it here, baby."
-"C-C-C-Colors, colors.
Colors."
-"Must get back to Rylos V!"
-This must be "Wet Side Story."
-[Laughs]
"Join me
in my dance hall of death!"
[Laughs]
-Yes, it's synchronized swimmingon ESPN.
The Wet Network.
-"Help me, Cecil!
Help me!"
"I'm coming, Beany Boy!
Here he comes!
I'm swimming
my little legs off!"
-"I will kill him!"
"I'm going to give you
such a water wedgie
you're not gonna ever forget."
-"An aqueous snuggie."
[Chuckles]
-"I can't believe he did that.
I just came over to say hello.
What would make a guy do that?"
-"Here. Breathe from me.
Take life from me.
Please."
-Oh, look.
They're standing four abreast.
-Oh, please!
-I'm sorry.
-[Laughs] "Uh,
we'll just stand here
'cause they're men,
and we're not.
-Take him to the other boat!
It's closer!
-"If it's so close, why
can't we see it in this shot?"
-"We don't want to be involved."
-Gee, what a wimp.
Can't even take
a seasoned diver with a knife.
-Boy.
-"I'm afraid you boys
will find only evil here."
-"I had him, Charlie.
I'm telling you,
I coulda killed him,
but he took my thumbs, Charlie."
-I don't know
how Tarzan does it.
-What happened?
-Well, I'm not sure.
-"Well, I started in theater,
moved on to summer stock,
and now I'm in this film. Why?"
-...held a gun on me,
and he took my wallet.
I tried to stop him,
we scuffled,
and he went overboard.
-Hmm.
-He didn't have any wallet
when I saw him.
-"It was eel skin.
Happy now, prune boy?"
-You see, there was nothing
of importance in the wallet.
-"You see,
'cause I'm lying my socks off."
-No, never.
-Where'd he come from?
-Probably swam, uh, out
from shore, I guess.
-"Ah, shore. Yeah.
That's it. That's right."
-"Yeah. Shore."
-"Hmm, I'm kind of skeptical."
-Hey.
-Seems like an awful long ways
to swim just for a few dollars.
-"Yeah."
-Last time I saw him,
he was heading out to sea.
-"How would you know?
You were drowning."
-Well, it doesn't really matter.It's all over now.
And I'm very grateful
this young man didn't get hurt.
-Come on, Tiger.
We'd better split for...
-"Don't call me that here,
Bunny, please."
-"Uh, tanks."
-Jeez.
-Get it?
-Boo!
-I tried to.
-You shouldn't have brought
the real one out here.
He knows!
We just struck out.
-Larry, will you
please settle down?
-"Get married, have some kids,
and take that
ridiculous hat off!"
-...concerned with
the problem at hand.
We've got to get that case back
before Lakopolous sends
his divers back for it.
Now, I know the scroll case
is watertight.
-Uh-huh.
-But if we lose it,
we really strike out.
-[Chuckles]
-"Think that's funny, huh?
Shoot yourself in the leg.
I'll be right back."
-"All done throwing up, spunky?"
-You sure know how
to worry a girl.
-I didn't know you cared.
-I don't.
-"We're gonna get a bigger boat,right?"
-...yacht party date
on such short notice.
-Yacht party?
-Huh?
-You're really nowhere.
Haven't you ever heard of one?
-Is it anything like
a rattlesnake hunt?
-What the heck does that mean?
-He's high.
-And I thought you were getting
an education in Arizona.
-We gotta split.
-"Yeah, kids just beat me up
a lot when I was a kid."
-Really?
-Yeah.
No, the movie.
-Oh.
-You do have a lot to learn.
They swing.
Really swing!
♪♪
-[Sobbing]
Creepy Girl!
Oh, Creepy Girl,
little creepy Girl!
-Geez, what's wrong, Tom Servo?
You look as upset
and downtrodden
as a little robot with
inarticulate limbs can look.
-Oh, it's Creepy Girl, Joel.
I just met a girl
named Creepy Girl,
and suddenly, I find...
-I smell a song coming on.
-[Sobbing]
Oh, Creepy Girl.
♪ Lyle Waggoner's a total jerk
♪ Second only to Tommy Kirk
♪ Could you find it
in your heart ♪
♪ To love a bot like me-e-e?
♪ That fishy story you tell
♪ Always makes me sleepy
♪ But that's just what I get fordating a girl that's creepy ♪
♪ My Creepy Girl
Oh, "C" is for that feeling
of uncertainty
for not quite knowing what
ethnic group you're from.
"R" is for the gifts you give meevery time you smile.
The first "E" is for,
uh, well, I don't really know,
but the second "E"
is really a grammatical thing,
'cause otherwise,
it would be "Crepy Girl,"
and where would that leave us?
The "P" is definitely
not for "platonic."
And "Y" -- because I love you.
♪ My Creepy Girl
Oh, what are you, Creepy Girl?
Are you French, Italian,
or one of those
swarthy Gypsy types?
Well, your accent suggests
a romance language,
but I can't be sure.
Well, we can definitely rule outa Germanic language,
but it's okay.
I'm a bot without a country.
All I know is that I love you.
I want to shout it
from the mountaintops.
Uh, but I'd have to get
back down to Earth
and actually climb a mountain.
Or they could just drop me off
on a mountain.
I don't care.
That would be okay
because I just need you.
♪ My Creepy Girl
♪ Won't you be mine?
♪ I'll give you scrolls and fishand Tinkertoys and wine ♪
♪ I'll ditch these guys
♪ If you'll be my Creepy Girl
♪ Be mine
♪ Before movie sign
[Alarm blaring]
♪ Whoa-whoo-hoo
-Say!
-Hey!
-She's got a Rorschach swimsuit.
-What do you see in it, Crow?
-I see the Creepy Girl.
-Oh.
I see cookie pants.
-I see trouble.
-Come on and do the dork!
-Hey, nice little boat
they landed there.
They killed it,
then they'll roast it later.
♪♪
Everybody get down.
-Ouch, owie, ow, hot pier!
Hot! Still hot wood! Nails!
Ouch, nails! Ow!
-Ouch!
-Well, this is the movie that --
one of the movies that shaped
Middle America's sexuality.
Deformed.
-Deformed.
-Yeah.
-I'd say something else,
but I won't.
It's cold out there.
-This is the place!
-Hell!
-In Arizona,
they call this a mirage.
♪♪
-I call it
drug-induced hysteria.
-Yeah.
-Charlie!
-Well, baby's come home!
-Mm-hmm!
-Nice!
-That guy must have something.
-Yeah, he doesn't shop
at Members Only or Ward's.
-Well, when in Rome...
-Yeah.
-Or Athens.
-What does that mean?
-I don't know.
-Hi, Charlie!
-It's been a long,
cold winter, Charlie.
-What does thatmean?
-Yeah!
-"Get over there.
I need some more chicks."
-"What did you say
your name was?
Yeah, I'm casting 'Caligula'
this summer,
so come on down."
-"This film was funded
by the Utah Film Board."
♪♪
-Hey, she's got a shaggy
diaper that leaks.
-[Laughs]
-Get it away from me!
-Hey, it's Ed Begley Jr.
Hi-keeba!
Hut! Hey! Ha!
Hi-ya!
-Hey, she lost
the bone in her neck.
Look at her flopping
around like that.
-[Chuckles]
-Oh, Charlie!
-"Come on.
Keep 'em coming.
Monkey love pile on me."
-Yeah!
-That must be what they mean by
"Five Easy Pieces."
-[Laughs] Oh, please.
-Looks like the cast of "Zoom."
-♪ Come on and
-♪ Zoom, zoom, zooma, zoom
-♪ Come on and zoom
-Hey.
-♪ Zoom, zoom, zooma, zoom
-Nice tablecloth there, huh?
-Yeah, very practical.
Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh! Ooh!
-Arsenio Hall!
-My posse!
-Go! Go!
-Hey.
-Oh, boy.
-Uh, Joel,
was this before cocoa butter?
-Yeah, I think so.
♪ Now, I know this
-Shirts
by the Renaissance Festival.
And King John,
who invites you to come down
and see
Robin Hood and Little John,
two never-was actors
performing bad skits.
-And bad music.
These guys are horrible.
-[Harmonizing off-key]
-"I'm gonna quit this band
and start a career in music."
-A couple of cheese
eaters there, yeah.
-♪ Wa-a-a-a-y
-♪ There's a new world
that's open for me ♪
-Oh, please.
-Bee Gees go bad...er.
-Worse.
-♪ And I haven't learned
the words to say ♪
"Hey, look, I'm 60.
[Light laughter]
-I'm still rocking.
Watch me."
-Yeah, tune in,
turn on, throw up.
-♪ Love, I know, I know
♪ Just can't tell when
the devil's on the fly ♪
-Now I know why drugs
were so big in the '60s.
-[Chuckles]
-You need 'em.
♪ I won't
♪ Pretend
♪ To sing
-♪ To sing
-♪ There's a new world
just openin' for me ♪
-♪ Me
-♪ While the girls prance
around in their BVDs ♪
[Chuckles]
What do you think, huh?
-Yeah.
-Pretty bad.
-You know...
-Lyrics by Aldous Huxley.
-Yeah.
-♪ Now I know
-♪ Most of these lyrics
are in "A" ♪
-I think they sent
the wrong people to Nam, Joel.
-Yeah.
-You know,
can somebody do us a favor
and push that guy's amp
in the water, maybe?
♪ We can't sing
-♪ Can't sing
-♪ There's a concept,
it's called harmony ♪
♪♪
♪ There's this word, obscurity
-Ha, look at those stupid legs.
They're stupid-looking.They're not real-looking at all.
-They look like puppets.
[All cheering]
Sieg Heil!
-Hey! Anybody who wants,
let's split to the beach
for volleyball!
-Ah, no thanks.
-Ah, you go ahead.
That's okay.
-Hey, lookin' out!
We're picking up
the sports channel.
-[Chuckles]
-Good shot!
-"Darn, and I forgot my shins."
-Yeah! Nice shot, baby!
Whoo!
-Whoo, whoo, whoo!
-"All the other kids hate me."
-Yeah.
-One Adam 12, see the man
whose shins were stolen.
-Should have been onboard
the scuba party.
You missed all the action.
-I heard what happened.
I wanted to say thanks
for helping Dad.
-"I had to see the man.
See the man,
corner of Wilmont and Crowley."
-That doesn't matter.
I appreciate what you did.
-Yeah.
-"I'll let you use my shins.
Deal?"
-Thanks.
-Wow!
-"Hey, wh-what did I do?"
-Oh, Joel, it's her!
-Who's that?!
-It's the Creepy Girl, Joel!
Ohh!
-Finally,a sultry woman with a nice body.
It's about time.
-Yeah.
-Going swimming
in threads like that?
-Watch how you talk about her.
That's mygirl.
Come on, follow the leader.
-And...d'oh!
-D'oh!
-She's none too happy.
-Mnh-mnh.
-Dibs.
I call dibs.
She's mine.
Back off, you clowns.
Come on.
I'll take you all on.
-"Let's try walking like her."
[Purrs]
-Hey! Hey!
Slow burn coming up.
♪♪
-Mm.
-Are you coming, Don, or not?
-[Chuckles]
-"Well, you'll do nicely.
Let's go have little
Marty Millners."
-"Remember what I said about
the last man on Earth?
Well, it's time."
-Are you unattached, like I am?
-You mean from reality?
-Yes, why?
-You don't catch on very fast,
do you?
-"What do you mean?"
-I'm afraid
I'm not used to the speed.
-Aw.
Don't tell me
you'rea drag, too.
-"No, just a drag queen."
-"Mardi Gras."
-Think you can handle
a beach party?
-I think it's worth a try.
-Okay. Let's go!
-Uh, what about him?
-We're not engaged.
-Ooh!
-Hmm!
-Okay.
-Loose morals, huh?
-Bunny.
-I get it.
Meanwhile on ESPN...
[Indistinct shouting,
laughter]
-"Everybody ditch
the little guy."
-"Uh, so, the game's over, huh?
Hey, hey, hey.
Come back here!
Hey,
what's the matter with me, huh?
Bad breath or something?"
-"I guess I'm kinda
messed up, after all.
Nobody likes me."
-Kid! Kid!
-There she is!
-Over here!
Over here!
-What is it, Tom?
-Is she okay?
I'm going out to get her, Joel.
Quick!
How do I get up?
-Do you swim?
-I gotta...
-Do you plan to stand there
and watch me die of pneumonia?
-"Well, both, actually."
-Oh, no.
♪♪
I'm -- I'll help you.
I can't help it, Joel.
-Now toss it.
-"Gee, what a nice guy."
-"Uh, excuse me.
Can I have my --
Uh, where are you going?
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna need that back.
Uh, excuse me.
Don't go too far with that.
It's my windbreaker.
I paid five bucks for that
at Ward's.
Please."
-Can I help?
-No, thank you.
Turn around.
-"Oh, thank you, God."
-Hmm.
He's kind of caught between
a rock and a hard place.
-Not yet.
-"Done?"
-Sorry.
I didn't mean to embarrass you.
-[Chuckles]
Isn't this movie enough?
-This is no time to be delicate.
It's a good thing
you stayed behind.
I was ready
to sacrifice my modesty.
-"Oh, we'll get to that,
my love."
-It seems I found out
my suit is not for swimming.
-Oh!
Joel, I have a question.
-Yeah?
-What happened to the
treasure hunt part of the film?
-Oh, the movie's over half over.
Maybe we'll learn something
about that.
-Still looking
for your little fish?
-Oh, you remembered?
-Mm-hmm.
-"Oh, yeah,
your deep-seated psychosis?
Of course."
We talked on the boat,
or, as I should say,
I talked,
but we never really met.
I'm Katrina Corelli.
-"And I'm cuckoo
for Cocoa Puffs."
-Nice to meet you, Don.
-"So, you're here on
an outpatient basis?
I like that."
-Huh?
-Your friends certainly know
how to enjoy themselves.
-They're a fun group.
They sure know
how to get their kicks.
-Why aren't you with them?
-"Well, I don't know
how to get my kicks."
-'Cause I wanted
to see you again.
-That's why you stayed?
-"Yeah, something like that."
-Like with my little fish,
I was afraidI wasn't going to see you again.
I'm glad I was wrong.
-Join us.
-"Join the party,
and we will rule the world!"
-How about it?
-"Well, I'm kind of kooked out
about that little fish
and everything.
It's all hot,
and it hurts and stuff."
-Hmm.
-His name is Angelo.
-"And he's a Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtle."
-We had something
very important to do,
and he's probably
looking for me right now.
He told me to wait
down at the pier.
-Where? Where?
-"Oh, he said something about
take a long, short walk
on a long pier."
-Something like that.
-Hmm. It's
a dysfunctional relationship.
-...I-I'd like to thank you.
-"I'd like
to thank the producers
and the directors, too."
-Has he been gone long?
-No, not very.
-Hmm.
-Don?
Would you like
to help me look for him?
-I'll help you!
I'll help you!
-Down this way.
Come on.
♪♪
-"So, did you call
Harry Callahan yet?"
-I need three more expert diversby this time tomorrow.
-"And two implants."
-You can leave that up to me.
What are we diving for?
-That's none of your business.
-"Well, how do we know
when we've found it?"
-...to dive,
not to ask questions.
We'd better get out of here.
-"Oh. Like this?"
-Like that.
"Arrgh!
Now I'm going to
go polish my suit."
-[Laughter]
That's funny!
-There she is again.
-You sure he came down here?
-Yes.
He said he had to meet
the man on the beach.
-Oh, that means he has
to go to the bathroom.
It's a guy thing.
-Yeah.
-Oh, I think I'd better
go back and wait for him.
Angelo has such a bad temper.
-Hmm.
-Angelo Dundee?
-Katrina.
Do you dig this Angelo?
-We're going to be married.
-Not what I asked you.
-"Do you dig him?"
-"I'm 1,000 feet tall!"
-Wow!
-Katrina!
Why didn't you wait
like I told you to?!
-Oh, you were gone so long --
-You still should have waited!
-She was worried. Now --
-You keep out of this!
-Hey, cool it, man!
-"Man!"
-You looking for trouble?!
-Please.
Let me take care of this.
-Alright, but if you run
into any static, just yell.
-"Just yell.
Call for the turtle boy."
-Yeah.
-You were very rude, Angelo.
-You had no right to be
on the beach with a stranger!
-Oh!
-Angelo!
Something is very wrong!
Who is this man
who pays you for doing nothing
and those men
you're always with?
-"Oh, he's from
paid programming.
This Carol Burnett thing isn't
gonna last forever, you know."
-It's none of your concern.
I never should have brought you
here in the first place.
-"I should have brought
Vicki Lawrence."
-Perhaps you're right, Angelo.
-Hmm?
-Oh?
What does that mean?
-I guess we could do this
right here and now.
-Alright, I'm all for it.
Hey, but we ran -- Hey!
-Went to black.
[Laughter]
-Hmm.
-Okay, now, Joel,
how do we comment on this
without getting
into big trouble?
-Well, you could use
a metaphor, maybe.
-Mmm. Raspberry red.
Lemon yellow.
-Mm-hmm.
-You read my mind.
-Choo-choo cherry?
-I just saw your sister.
-D'oh!
"Oh, I'm tired. I'm" --
-"Quick!
Get a pin down his throat.
Trach him!"
-He's tired from
all that make-out.
-"Well, I don't
even have an agent.
I just saw the ad
in the trade dailies,
and here I am."
-Hey, clambake!
[Chuckles]
-Fade out, man.
-Fade out?
-Who's minding the store?
-Jerry Lewis!
-Harbor patrol
has the afternoon off.
-Where'd you split to?
-I felt like
cutting out for a while.
-Hmm.
Using a lot of jargon.
-What are they talking about?-She's hung up with another guy.
-Hi, Bob!
-"Hi, net girl."
-You like this suit?
-"Mm, yes!"
-Wild!
-Don't you dare speak to me.
-"Okay."
-Wow!
-It's her again!
It's Creepy Girl!
-Oh.
Forget her.
-Oh, I can't.
I just can't.
-"Hi, lower life forms."
-Hello, Don.
I've decided to accept
your invitation.
-"To the beheading?"
-If it's still open.
-Aw, is it?
-Sam, you've got to be
the mother of all pigeons.
-Yeah, tell them to stop
messing up our statues.
-Don't mind him.He's got a language all his own.
-Yeah, he took a shell in 'Nam.
-Aren't you going to introduce
me to your playmate, Don?
-Hmm.
-Katrina, this is everybody.
-"This is Miss January.
This is everybody.
This is this."
-Everybody, this is Katrina.
-That was real dandy, sport.
-Hmm?
-I'm Charlie Moss.
-"I collect custom showgirls."
But you can forget about him.
He's ready for a wheelchair.
-"Hey, come on.
I'm 17.
Cut out
the good-natured ribbing."
-...if nobody will introduce us?
-Meet the daughter of Satan.
-"I got to change my drift net."
-Did I say something wrong?
-Where's Angelo?
-I don't know.
I don't really care.
-Because of me?
-That,
and a man named Lakopolous.
-What about Lakopolous?
-"He'll thrash her
from top to bottom-us."
-Doing what?
-Diving, I think.
That's about the only thing
Angelo's ever done.
Why?
-Could that be the diver
you tangled with?
-"I dare not tell them that
they speak of my family."
-Who's Lakopolous?
-"I'll close up his esophagus."
-Then you know
of his reputation?
-I'm afraid we do.
I wonder why Lakopolous
needs a diver.
-"I saw it on Ted Coppel-ous."
-Help! Help!
-A baby's cry for help.
-[Screams]
-"Help, my career is drowning!"
-Hang on!
I-I'm coming!
-"Wait, I'll get my jack--
No, I don't have it.
Aw."
-"I'll stay here
and protect the harem."
[Laughter]
-He's so funny
in the active tragedy,
in the middle
of something horrible.
-Oh, there he goes.
Hey, wait.
He's got salvage rights.
-"Now, was that you who cried?"
Keep her butt above water.
That's good.
-Nice!
"She's better than
that tarpon I caught in Bimini.
This is a keeper.
I'm gonna get out
my filet knife." Ha-ha-ha!
-A little surf-and-turf action.
-You betcha.
-[Groaning]
"I was saved...
by the stinky guy?!"
[Laughter]
-"She almost died.
Ah, she's got water
in her lungs.
Brain damage."
-"And that's for you,
Moe and Larry.
Spinach chins."
-D'oh!
-You can bet
if shewas drowning,
they would have all gone in!
-Unite! Unite! Unite!
-Whoop, whoop,
whoop, whoop, whoop!
-Crazy Popper, Crazy Popper.
The slap-happiest game, ever.
-"Hey, I didn't get slapped."
-"Get him, girls.
He hit Buddy."
This looks like
a strange version
of "Lysistrata."
-Mm-hmm.
♪♪
-[Chuckles] "Follow 'em.
Do whatever they do.
Who cares?"
The chicks are up in arms.
They've left
their fields and barns.
They're marching on the farms
because kids won't
drink enough milk.
-I would.
-When you're a Jet,
you're a Jet all the way.
Hey!
♪ There ain't nothin'
like a dame ♪
♪ We got sunlight on the sand
-♪ Nothing looks like a dame
♪ Nothing cooks...
Now, this must be on the way
to the Greenwich Village
Halloween Party.
-Yep.
-I'm thinking.
-"I hope I get it.
I really hope I get it."
-For some un-explicable reason,
a deep-seated call from nature
causes these lemmings
to follow each other
off the edge
of the high cliff.
-"Man, I got a pole
with a capital 'O'."
-Whoo-hoo!
Is he a time traveler?
-And now Red in the silent spot.
Red's a fisherman, and...
Uh-oh.
-Uh-oh.
♪♪
-Mm.
Too small.
Have to throw it back.
-Yeah!
-Whoo!
-Woo-woo!
-[Howls]
-"She hit Big Jake."
-I feel a number coming on.
-Hey, we better
do something but quick.
-Yeah.
-Let's do something.
-Hey, it's Gloria Estefan
and the Catalina
Deus Ex Sound Machina.
♪♪
-"What a drag."
-"Hey, gang.
Maybe if we do this,
it'll be okay.
Ready?
Five, six, seven, eight."
-He's the paid --
He's the only professional
dancer they hired,
so they got to use him.
-Cassie!
-Is that Deney Terrio?
-Yeah.
He's the guy who taught
John Travolta to dance.
-Girls just can't resist
the frolicking vibes
of a hot guy.
Neither can I.
-Look at the body on him.
-[Laughs] Geez.
-The girls begin
to become aroused
by the provocative gyrations
of the shamed males
of the village.
♪♪
-That's, um...
-Yeah.
-You know, I still am having
a hard time figuring out
what this has to do
with any scroll.
-I don't know.
Oh, yeah.
-Hey, gang, let's gather
'round for the next scene!
-Hey,
it's the same shot as before.
I love that.
-[Chuckles]
-Continuity gets it in this one.
♪♪
-Wow.
They're dancing forapartheid.
-Yeah, it's to raise money
for the National Front.
-It's the
"Keep Mandela in Prison" dance.
-Right.
-They want to play Sun City,
I guess.
-P.W. Botha back in office!
♪♪
-Ah, the clean smell of kids
who know they rule the world.
♪♪
-Grab that lace, will ya?
-Oop.
-Too bad.
Next time.
♪♪
-I'm getting down.
Oh, sounds like the tape's
getting eaten here.
-Oops.
-Oh, hm, uh...
-8-track. Um, you want to tie
that up over there, Servo?
-I'm trying to bite it, though.
My arms don't work.
Darn!
-♪ Love has never been
figured mathematically ♪
♪ 'Cause the business
of the heart's ♪
-And her name is Sybil.
-♪ The Book of Love
-And all her friends.
-♪ I think they'll learn
-Oh, this is great.
You know,
now that she's so famous,
it's fun to see
these old clips, huh?
-Yeah. Ha!
Who is she?
-From humble origins,
she went on to...
-Obscurity.
-Yeah.
-♪ That's the way it should be
That is the way it should be.
-♪ Boys would like to think
they make the girls... ♪
-Hey, they grew up to be
Jim and Tammy Bakker.
♪ And the girls end up mad
but they seem... ♪
-♪ Let's not have talent,
let's do away with fun ♪
♪ Let's all be white,
really white ♪
♪ Snowy white
-Hey, I checked out
the Book of Love one time,
and it was really hard
to find in the library,
'cause there's not
a lot of copies of it.
There's these notes in the
margins in these pages -- huh?
-Shut him up.
-Just watch the movie, okay?
♪ Let's not fight it
-♪ And we're all white
♪ And swing to the right
♪ Hey!
-Oh, wow!
-Here comes
Carmine Ragusa again.
-Say!
-Uh-oh.
-Hiya, Shoil!
-Hey, do the jerk!
The idiot!
The moron!
-The potato-up-the-butt dance!
The dickweed!
-Do the white male reality!
The Donald Hollinger!
-Yeah!
Do the "That Girl"!
Yoo-hoo!
-♪ Girls would like
to think that boys ♪
♪ Just don't understand
-Hey!
-♪ Feminine schemes don't work
out just how they planned ♪
♪ The silly little things that
almost cause us to break up ♪
-It's just one big, sunny,
fun-filled Bataan Death March.
♪ The Book of Love
-♪ The Book of Love
♪ I bet they'll learn
♪ Let's not rewrite it
-Don't rewrite anything.
-♪ Oh, let's not fight it
-We never change.
Why should we?
We're on top of the world!
-♪ Let's get together
♪ That's the way it should be
♪ The book of Love
-White love.
-♪ I bet they'll learn
-It's good, isn't it?
Tell me it's good.
Come on.
-♪ Oh, let's not fight it
♪ Let's get together
-Why did the Titanichave
to sink and this didn't?
-♪ That's the way it should be -Irony.
-You know what the difference isbetween the Titanic and this?
-What?
-Titanic had talent.
-Ohh!
[Light laughter]
-Thank you!
Thank you!
You've been a great crowd,
Catalina!
Tip your waitresses!
Good night, everybody!
-Oh!
-Oh, boy.
-Oh, the old suitcase gag.
-This is a classic.
-The suitcase, and, uh --
Huh?! Oh!
[Indistinct talking, laughter]
-And then -- Aah!
-Oh, yes!
-That's so funny.
-This guy makes the film for me.
-Yeah.
-He makes a film for me,
too, but it's...
-Not this one, huh?
-No.
-Okay, let's can it.
Plot's back now.
-A pasty film on the...
-Hm.
-The youth of today,
spent like so many
shell casings
on the battlefield of love.
-Uh-huh.
-Remember,
I'll do all the talking.
-And you do
the interpretive dance.
-Good man.
Well, good morning, everyone!
-It was.
-Hi, kids!
[Laughs]
I forgot.
-Hi, Mr. Duval.
-Oh, what a lovely day
for basking in the sun.
-What are you doing here, Dad?
-I just thought I'd take
my morning constitutional.
-Oh, here on the beach?
-At 2:00 in the afternoon?
-[Laughs]
-Can't fool you, can I, son?
-No, but I've got a feeling
you're gonna try.
-D'oh!
-Well, truth of the matter is,
I'm here for a reason.
-Ah.
-You see, I'd like
to do something to put
a little zing in the weekend
for you kids.
-Might give you some bennies,
yellowjackets, or goofballs.
-What do you have in mind, Dad?
-How about a scuba diving party?
-Scuba parties are nothing new.
-How about naked
with straight razors
and nitrous oxide in the tanks?
-...your friends aboard my yachtby 10:00 tomorrow morning.
How does that sound?
-Wild!
-Yeah!
-And you'll be diving
for lost treasure.
Items worth $5 and up.
-Mm, we're dumb!
-And here is the grand prize.
-It's a stick of dynamite.
-What is it?
-You get to throw it at me.
-Oh, it's an old map case.
-Now, for every one of these
we'll find,
we'll donate a penny
to Jerry's Kids.
-The diver who brings this up
wins the grand prize and $100!
-100 bucks?
-Wow!
What I could do with $100!
-There ain't nothing wrong
with her $100 couldn't fix.
-Don't forget --
on board by 10:00!
-And don't forget
your plot device.
-Dad, I've got
that funny feeling again.
-Take an aspirin, son.
-Take a whole bottle.
-Okay.
I'm with you so far.
But I'll be watching you, Dad.
-Hm.
-Good boy.
-He's not even my son, you know.
He's Marty Milner's.
-Well, the rest is
up to them now.
If they don't come up
with that scroll,
you can bet Lakopolous'
divers will.
-A flag known as crapolous.
-There's no way that guy
could make something funny
out of that situation.
-Nope.
-It's just direct.
I don't see it, frankly.
-He's a comic genius.
-I don't see him making --
-Ohh!
[Laughter]
-Meanwhile, in Gotham's harbor,
the Exxon Valdez.
-They should be coming up soon.
-What, our lunch?
-Been diving for over an hour,
and there's no case!
-Patience, Lawrence, patience!
-Lawrence.
-Hey, everybody,
I found a new script!
And this one's funny!
-Look, th--there's bobby pins
down there and Band-Aids,
and there's a lotta hair
in the drain.
-Mm!
-What do they got?
-...that we ain't got?
-Courage!
-Next divers.
-That's the third time
they come up with this thing.
-Time's running out.
-He wanted to see time fly!
[Chuckles]
-Charlie Sheen in
"Navy SEALs" --
a Golan-Globus production.
-Hey, it's us again.
-Arthur, I have a splendid idea.
Why don't they all
go down together
for one final effort?
-Without tanks.
-Sound idea.Is that agreeable with everyone?
-Yeah.
-Very agreeable.
Thanks for asking.
Appreciate it.
-Mm-hmm.
-We are here
to spoil everything.
-Over there!
-Hm?
-They must be after the scroll.
You see any other divers?
-Uh, only you.
-We can't afford to guess.
Let's find out.
♪♪
-Huh? What? Down here?
Oh, okay.
♪♪
-Oh!
-Oh, there he is again!
[Laughs]
-This should --
This should be great.
-Oh, this must be a good one.
-Mm.
-Huh?!
-What?
-Look,
it's Dino, Desi, and Billy.
-Hey, Sinatra got 'em a gig!
-At the bottom of the harbor.
He must be tripping.
-I'd think so.
-Entertain all those other guys
at the bottom of the harbor.
-Yep.
-Lakopolous should've
made his move by now.
-Yeah, well, I guess
they figured we we were just...
-Oh, they got sandwiches.
Oh, wait.
They got that pistol
from the Man From Glad.
-I really know how
to handle guys like that.
-Oh!
-You got me.
-Where is it?!
-You're a very sneaky man.
-Is it safe?
-Oh, I'm with you.
-I don't have time
to fool around!
Where's the scroll?
-Should we give him
three guesses?
-I don't see why we should.
-Oh, don't make him mad.
-Oh, we got to split, guys.
-I can't watch this.
-Let's go.
They look tough!
-Yeah.
-Oh, man.
Oh, I think
it's his sarcasm sequencer.
So, I'm gonna have to field-
strip you, little buddy.
Come here.
-Hey! Oww!
Hey, that hurt.
Gimme that back.
-Hey, neat!
I'd like a wing, please.
-Oh, the overlords are calling.
Look sharp, you guys.
-Oh, hi, Joel.
Uh, just thought
you'd like to see
what we got going on down here.
I think you know everybody.
This is Jerry,
and that's Sylvia.
And you know Joel and the bots,
so let's get started, and...
Oh, Jerry, you haven't even
touched your sandwich.
It's good stuff.
And Sylvia, coffee?
Just all you want.
Free refills.
Free ref-- Oh, we're gonna
have a lot of fun.
So let's get started.
We've got fun,
easy-to-plan stuff here.
Now, now, Sylvia,
back me up on --
you know what I'm talking about,this one.
Are you with me on this?
These guns
that are stored underwater?
This method with the baggie
and the...
It makes no sense.
It's totally impractical.
It's just outmoded stuff.
We have nothing to do.
But this product
that I'm giving you
the opportunity to get in
on here --
it's a triple-ply polycarbonate
reinforced substrate.
As a matter of fact,
it's the, uh...
type of material used
by the astronauts
on "It's About Time."
It's very --
-Well, Fred!
Fred,
how's our new venture going?
-Uh, Frank. Frank.
-Oh, whatever.
-Oh, well, it's, uh...
-Don't mind me.
I'm just going to sit in
and observe.
-Okay.
-Go on with your presentation.
-Okay, good.
Uh, you get some of that...
I think we got some...
Wisconsin cheese log there.
Uh, it's, uh...
Same thing with him.
Okay, uh, we've got, uh...
Oh, this is, uh, for --
for storing, uh, hand grenades.
Uh, this is perfect.
It fits on --
And we have the gel in it
that stores it free.
And look, it fits p-perfectly.
Uh...
It's, uh...
Okay.
And we have the, uh,
this salad.
It's fruit salad.
Stays perfectly well.
Never with...
Ohh, well.
Here, let me just --
just take --
Put that there.
And this is even better, here.
This will stay right on there.
There's no --
[Laughs nervously]
Here.
Let's take that...
up there with the...
thing, and we'll put that --
Oh, maybe I should do a joke.
You ever notice how the mole men
with the thing and the...
coffee with the...
put the --
-Frank. Frank!
Frank!
-Huh?
-Why don't you just pack it all
in here?
It's, uh...
It's okay.
Why don't we just start
cleaning up?
I, uh...
give you points for your -- yourlittle party here, but, uh...
-You're gonna hurt me,
aren't you?!
-No, Frank. I give you --
-You're gonna be mean to me!
-No, I'm not.
Why do you pull away?
-You're gonna be mean.
You're gonna hurt me,
and it's gonna be humiliating.
It's gonna hurt and stuff.
-Look -- Look, Frank.
You -- You've got a lot to learnabout being a mad scientist.
And -- And, you know, I...
I think I'll buy one
of your melon ballers.
-Well, actually,
there's some melon
right up there.
That'll be perfect.
-Frank!
Frank's going to be
having a little pain.
We'll be right back.
-Aaaaaaaaaaah!
♪♪
[Water splashes]
-Oh!
-Charlie!
-Ooh!
♪♪
-Huh?
-Oh, my karate pinkie!
-Got it.
-I got the implant.
This will launch my empire.
♪♪
-Hang on!
-Clean deck, man!
-Oh!
-Tell your friends, dude.
[Women shout]
♪♪
-Oh, black water,
keep on rolling.
♪♪
-Any resemblance
to a real action sequence
is purely coincidental here.
-Arthur?!
-Once you get caught
between the moon
and New York City...
-Did they get the case?
-Oh, yes.
I saw them take it away
from Charlie.
-They took my thumbs!
They -- Oh, no, wait.
They're still here.
-What's in that case?
-Whatever it was,
it sure must've been worth
a lot of bread.
-Toast.
I want to know --
what's it all about?
-Alfie.
-Isn't this exciting?
-I'd like an explanation,
too, Mr. Duval.
I mean, this is the second time
in the last few days
I've almost gotten
myself killed.
-Yeah, lots of other stuff, too!
-...I'll explain a little later.
♪♪
-Will you put your hands down,
Lawrence?
-D'oh!I don't want to play patty-cake.
-Well, we really
shouldn't feel too badly.
The fates were against us.
-And it cost us
half a million bucks.
-Aw.
-Boy, the ballgames
I could've seen with that dough!
-You know, I don't think
I want to live in a world
filled with adults anymore.
-Not a chance!
-Nothing's right.
-You're hurting.
-Yeah, that's what
I'm afraid of.
-There's always the chance
of the police tracing
the stolen scroll
back to my folks.
-Are you sure this
is a real scroll?
-Hey, who's to say what's real
and what's not real, man?
-And besides,
we heard Dad talking about it.
-We can thank
the screenwriter for that.
-This case has been in the waterfor more than a few hours.
The scroll we thought
we were diving for was a phony.
-I just got a flash.
-A hot flash.
He's going through menopause.
-...merchandise, man,
they're gonna be out for blood.
-Man, everything's
coming down on me today.
-Let's unload this hot potato
on the fuzz.
-Cool it.
Get the fuzz into this,
and his folks end up in jail.
-I can't use this lingo anymore.
-Cops are already suspicious,
especially of Lakopolous.
-He's totally "psycho-polous."
-If your old man wants it
so bad, be my guest.
I-I haven't got the blood
to spare for those vultures.
-Got the hair for it.
-That's no good.
The minute Dad gets it back,
the temptation will be
too much for him.
-And the Four Tops
and The Spinners.
-...is too much
for him to turn down.
-For my bread, you should've
left it where you threw it
instead of going back
to dive for it.
-Please, I implore you,
shut up!
-I have no right to say this...
-God, your hair smells good.
-...well, to scare the larceny
out of your folks
once and for all.
-Scare the what?
-And get Angelo
and Borman arrested.
-I'm ready to try anything
as long as it doesn't involve
Mother and Dad or the police.
-Or farm animals.
-We know they want
the real scroll.
What we've got to do
is make sure that they know
that we've got it.
-I'm not about to have 'em take
out their frustrations on me!
-Aw, shut up!
-And lose my image?
-What image?
-What's the play?
-Oh, it's "Twelfth Night."
-We try and smoke out
Angelo and Borman.
Bound to be around someplace.
Let's find Tina
and some of the kids.
-These kids today
with their loud music
and hula hoops,
fax machines!
-Oi, buddy.
-I don't know.
-For those of you
following along
in the Syd Field
screenplay workbook,
that last scene
was the plot point
setting up the third act.
Now this.
-Mayberry, after hours.
-No shirt, no shoes, no script.
-Okay, uh, "Hello, Muddah.
Hello, Faddah.
here I am at, uh, Catalina."
That's not it.
-Unh-unh, unh-unh.
-Ehh.
♪♪
-Mm-hmm.
Mm!
-Zack Norman as Sammy
in "Chief Zabu."
-Hm!
Uh-oh.
-It's the big guy.
♪♪
-I have to sit like this
since the implant.
♪♪
-I'm watching you, crayon head.
-Oi! Ouch! Oww!
-Ouch-ee! Oh, oh, hot!
Hot!
-Ooh, asphalt!
Oh! Ouch! Oh!
-[Panting]
-Any luck?
-Nothing.
Here come the bunnies.
Maybe they did better.
-Hoppin' down the bunny trail.
-Hey, it's Charlie's Angels,
plus a smart one!
-Nobody! At least,
not anybody who looks like
the two you fought with
on the Lira.
-Keep looking.
-Move out, troops!
-Oh, it's"McMillan & Wife & Wife & Wife."
-Can I talk to you a minute?
-What?
-Talk!
Just a minute.
-We gotta go.
What's wrong?
-Uh, I'm pregnant.
-About yesterday...
I'm sorry I slapped you.
And I wasn't really
drowning, either.
-Oh, yeah, and I'm not acting.
-I forgot all about that.
-Really?
-Really.
But you do pack
a pretty mean wallop.
-Oh, don't rub it in.
-I was gonna say,
"for a pretty girl."
-Ah, but you're ugly.
-Listen, Charlie Moss
has got a groovy sister.
And you know who else thinks so?
-The football team?
-Tad.
-Well, I apologized to him, too.
-Oh-whoa!
-Only first.
-Oh!
-It's them!
-[Gasps]
-Go find Charlie.
Quick.
-Right now!
-Hmm, hey, Charlie.
-I'll take him on.
I know I can.
I'll do it.
-Yeah!
- I will, I will, I will.
♪♪
-Hm, hm, hm, hm, hm. Hm?
-Hm! Lucky!
Open table.
♪♪
-Hmm.
-How come he got a menu already?
Lucky.
-Ugh! Peach daiquiri!
So, that's what
I drank last night.
Hm.
Tasted pretty good.
-Nice spit take, dude.
-We've got to get the scroll...
-I'm still waiting
for my spinach omelet.
-And no slip-up this time.
-Hi!
-Uh, yes, I am.
You?
-I've been looking for you.
-It's Creepy Girl!
-Don't make any heroic moves,
my friend.
-It's too late
to rewrite the script.
-Hand it over.
-Angelo!
What are you doing here?
-Working, being evil.
Shut up!
-I don't have time for games.
-And I haven't got time
for the pain.
-Angelo!
-Aw, man.
Everybody's coming
down on Angelo.
♪♪
-Thank you.
-Creep.
♪♪
-After him, teen gang!
-Yeah!
[Laughter]
-D'oh! Oof!
-When you're a Jet,
you're a Jet all the way.
-Splendid, son!
-It's a Catalina army knife.
-That's the Boy Scot motto.
Always be prepared.
-And effeminate.
-We'll take care of the garbage.Go get 'em, Don.
Can you handle this
for Mr. Duval?
-It's the land fuzz!
-Some call them land pigs.
-You bunnies stay here.
Duty calls your master away.
-Hm? What'd he mean by that?
Okay, people.
Everybody wear eye protection.
There's a lot of loose ends
flying together
all at once here.
-Wow,
this Main Street, U.S.A. parade
is really getting thin.
-[High-pitched] Hi, folks!
-That's not Mickey --
that's Nicky!
-Hey, he's running into
the Haunted Mansion.
-Oooh!
I'm your Ghost Host.
-Owie! Ouch!
-Oww! Oww! Ouch! Hot!
-Owie, owie, owie!
-Oh, ooh, ouch, hot, hot!
-D'oh. D'oh. D'oh. D'oh!
Pratfall, anyone?
Pratfall?
I got 'em all!
-Ouch, ouch, oww!
-Owie, ow, ooh!
It hurts!
-Hm, no exit through there.
-Hm.
-Alright.
Come on, come on!
-Hyah!
-Nice tag.
-D'oh, hey, lady!
-They put the skateboard
in the film!
-Well, wow!
Oh!
-Don't snag on me.
Don't snag on me!
-Eat it, boy.
Eat it.
-Oh!
-Oh, no. No.
-Look out, Mr. Ferguson!
-Jerry, no!
-I'm sorry, Mr. Ferguson!
-Oh, here it goes!
[All shouting]
-You got me all wet, boy.
-Well, guess he's swimming
back to Greece.
♪♪
-Little late, aren't you, buddy?
-Take a rest, friend.
You've provided enough
comic relief.
Thank you,
Corky the water clown,
for making us laugh
at love...again.
-What do you think you're doing?
-I've got you this time, Duval.
-Will you take these
silly things off my wrist?
-I'm the silly thing!
-I've waited a long time
for you make a slip.
Now I've got you!
-What's this all about?
Who are you?
-Fingers O'Toole,
insurance investigator.
-FBI. Pratfall Division.
-This man is my prisoner.
-And what's the charge?
-Grand theft.
-And wearing an ascot.
-Look, you don't even know
what you're talking about.
-You stole the scroll
from the collection,
and it's in that case
you're holding.
-Oh, wow.
He's holding, dude.
-Hmm.
-Hey, cool!
A Bon Jovi poster.
-It's kind of like a peashooter,isn't it?
-Mm, a big one.
-It's gone!
-My career!
-It was in there.
I know it was in there!
-Why me?
Why me all the time?
-Where did it go?
-I don't believe it.
-I'm Iggy Pop.
-Oh, boy.
-Hey, the script's
in Braille now.
-He looks about 40.
-Closing time, young fella.
-The guy who lives here
wants to go to bed.
-Sure is beautiful.
-Yes, sure is.
♪♪
-Man, I sure love that
old snot-rag of a...
-Huh?!
[Whistle blows]
-So, you know, mi amor...
-The pain! The pain!
[All groaning]
Stealing art!
Win one, lose one --
famous American cliché.
-Shaving my head.
-I told you it would be
a long walk home.
-Didn't I tell you that?
-Enjoy?
-Oh, you promiscuous
manly robot monster.
-Kill him! Kill him!
-Musical newspaper from Japan.
And look!
Zack Norman as Sammy
in "Chief Zabu" --
it says it right there.
Oho!
-Oh, wow.
-Yikes!
♪♪
-Eh!
Let's quit.
I'm hemorrhaging.
-Hey, Mom, Dad,
you got any rhythm left?
We're out.
-How?
-How did it get out of my case,
back into the museum?
-Go figure.
-As Charles would say,
"Don't knock it, Dad."
Perhaps it's best forgotten,
anyway.
Lakopolous has
sailed away forever,
perhaps a little bit wiser
for his experience.
-I doubt it.
-There's only one answer, Anne.
Somebody up there likes us.
-No, dear.
I think someone loves us.
-Well, it's not me.
-Well, what now?
What's left for us?
-Drug running?
-Not one single prospect
on the entire island.
-Prostitution?
-I've searched high and low.
The pigeons have all flown away.-Slumlords?
-Well,
you could always go to work.
-Y-- Work?!
-Huh?!
-Oh.
-As Charles might say,
that's a boss idea.
You know,
it's time I did some retiring.
-Oh, there's that
Louis Nye look-alike contest.
We could dance goofy.
♪♪
-Ah, I've outgrown
this pratfall stuff.
It was just a phase.
Now I'm a swingin' cat!
Yeah!
-Hey, it's a skinhead!
Get Geraldo!
-[Chuckles]
-Say!
-Oh, look at Creepy Girl.
Doesn't she look great
in a hairdo like that?
I like her in a flip.
♪♪
-Oh, he's down to one girl, huh?He's cutting back.
Oh, nobody wants to dance
with the big stinky guy.
-Shirt's louder than the music,
isn't it?
-Yeah.
-Ahh, dork shack!
-Geek shack.
-Dork shack, baby, yeah!
-That's where it's at.
-Got a movie
that's as long as a whale.
-It's about to set sail!
Whoo!
-A plot hole
that's as big as a whale.
-Huzzah! King John invites
you to the Ren Festival.
Come see 300 years
crammed into one place.
Meet the people you snagged on
in high school.
Bring your own tights
or wear some of our own.
-Uh, principals to the front,
please.
Extras in back.
There you go.
Thank you.
-Oh, it was only a movie.
-What?! Oh!
-Wow.
-It wasn't real?
-Oh, it was real, too.
-Um, wait.
I'm having some trouble here.
-I was right in
the middle of that.
-Oh, brother.
-So, a good movie deserves
a good encore of the cast.
-I wonder if we're gonna see
the fish again here at the end.
-What fish?
Oh, that's right.
-Fish from the beginning,
remember?
-Yeah, and the scroll.
That was good.
-I still don't really
get what happened.
-Um...
-We got to do something
to understand this.
This was just bizarre.
Had something to do
with a scroll.
-I've been doing a lot
of foreign films
with a lot of subtitles and --
-Where did the scroll go to?
And how did it get
back where it was?
-They're a lot easier to --
This is harder than
a Werner Herzog film
to figure out.
-I think it's importantthat we experienced it together.
Don't you?
And we shared.
-Yeah.
We'd better get out of here.
-Let's go.
-"AMF Vomit"?
-Carry me.
-Oh, that's "Voit."
-No.
-Please?
Come on.
♪♪
-Man, that was a really
confusing movie,
wasn't it?
-Well, no.
Um...not really.
I only have one question,
actually.
-What's that, Crow?
-What the Sam Hill was going on?-Yeah!
-Well, which part of the movie
did you have a hard time with?
-Well, I was doing okay until
the opening credits ended,
and then I thought
it was like a cartoon
with really good animation.
-You know, I'm confused, too.
The only thing
that made any sense to me
was that darling Creepy Girl.
I can't seem to get her
out of my mind.
♪ Ooh, ooh, ooh
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, uh-huh ♪
♪ Creepy Girl
-Uh, Tommy? Tom.
♪ My Creepy Girl
-Stop the music.
Cambot, cut it out.
-Oh, sorry.
-Uh, very good,
Mr. Tommy Servo Tune, there.
I had a feeling this was
gonna happen with this.
So, on the way back
from the theater,
on the spiral on down...
Would you just move over,
you guys?
-Oh, excuse me.
-I took the liberty
of making this, uh,
chart of the film, okay,
so we could figure it out
a lot better.
-Ooh! Ahh! Ooh!
-Yeah, great.
Thank you,
you spinach-chins.
Anyway, this is gonna
make us all feel better.
So, let me just start
explaining it.
We can help each other.
Okay. Act One.
Uh, the, um, Allan Sherman
wannabe in the Crayola hat --
that's this guy down here...
-Ah.
-...uh, steals the "scroll"
from Pegboard Mansion.
-Uh-huh.
-Okay, uh, Tom?
-Uh...
-Oh!
Oh, then he hands it off
to the Louis Nye guy,
the Billy De Wolfe wannabe
with the Jim Backus mouth
and the upgrade wife aboard
the thinnest ship in the Navy.
-Ah, I remember now.
Upgrade Wife drew a fake of it,
which they planned to pawn off
on, uh, Mr. Van-opolous.
-Ahh! Okay.
Slamdance Cosmopolous.
-Ah, Do-the-Worm-Acropolis.
-Will you two stop-olous?
-Okay, now.
-[Laughs]
Then, uh, Lockjaw Jim Backus
and, uh, Crayola Head here
get in a big plastic hassle
with Lyle Waggoner.
And the, uh...
script or the scroll
ends up going south.
-Oh, h-hold on, Joel.
You're getting way
ahead of yourself.
What about Tommy Kirk meeting
the Creepy Girl on the boat
and the sensitive soliloquy
about the little fishy?
-Uh, w-- wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Uh, you're both forgetting,
uh, to mention
all the singing and dancing
with Little Richard
tripped up on goofballs.
-Okay, hold it, hold it.
What the heck did that
have to do with anything?
The entire plot was hinged
on the relationship
between the Creepy Girl
and Tommy Kirk.
-No, listen.
The whole emotional thrust
of the second act was
when Lockjaw throws
the hullabaloo
come-treasure-hunt to get
the scroll back in his posses--
-No, mnh-mnh. No.
Unh-unh, wait a --
What about the dysfunctional
relationship
that the kid
who looked like Jim Bakker,
you know, kind of, uh, shared
with Billy De Wolfe and --
I thought that was the emotionalcenter of the film.
-Yeah, what about it?
-Crow, that was the emotional
Tootsie center of the film!
-Oww!
-Oww, d'oh, d'oh!
-Man, I'm teed off.
-No fair!
-Let me go get the letters.
-Uh, Joel? Joel, Joel!
The letter's right here
on the desk.
-Okay, okay.
Alright.
-Read that letter, will ya?
-Just try to calm down here.
-Come on, now.
-Okay.
Oh, this -- this is great.
I'm sorry I got
kind of crazy there,
but, uh...
-So am I.
-Okay, this is
a really neat letter.
Let's put it up
on the screen there, Cambot.
It says, "Dear Joel,
Tom Servo, Gypsy, Cambot,
and of course Crow,
we think this may be
a first for your show.
We met, we spent time together,
and fell in love
watching 'MST-3000',
and now we're getting married."
-Aww.
-Aww!
That's wonderful!
-"We're hoping you can make it
to the nuptial festivities,
but if the evil scientists
won't let you guys out,
please send a picture of Crow
for us to keep..."
-Oh, that's fabulous.
-..."and cherish
as a precious reminder.
Tell Crow the door is ajar."
Okay.
-Aww!
-Thanks.
-And here --
Put this up, Cambot.
Here's the wedding announcement.
We're gonna have to block out
some of this...
-Like their names.
-...so we don't get a bunch
of MSTies there.
-Yeah.
-But, anyway, I thought that --
-It's the Trumps,
and it's in New York!
-Is it an open bar?
-I think that was super cute,
cool, and really romantic.
-Yeah, isn't romance wonderful?
-Yeah.
-Hit it, Cambot!
♪ Ooh, ooh
♪ Creepy Girl
Oh, Creepy Girl.
My eyes pour out
to you in heaves
and droves of iridescent shapes
and stars in the sky.
But I don't care, Creepy Girl.
I got hit in the head
with a crowbar,
and I just don't see
straight anymore.
All I know is, I love you.
-Bad movie.
Uh, good fruit salad.
Uh, push the button,
Martha Stewart.
-[Speaks gibberish]
♪♪